These auralin and novodra columns violate the first rule of tidiness only,
这些 Auralin 列和 Novodra 列只违反了整洁度的第一条规则
that each variable forms a column.
即 每个变量构成一个列
There are three variables here: treatment, auralin or novodra,
这里有三个变量: 治疗、Auralin 或 Novodra
start dose, for example 41 units here,
起始剂量 (例如 这里 41 个单位)
and then end dose,
和结束剂量
for example 48 units here.
例如 这里 48 个单位
So since there are three variables here there should be three columns
由于这里有三个变量 应该分为三列
and there are currently two and both contain two variables.
目前有两列且两列均包含两个变量
The auralin column contains the start and end dose for auralin patients and
Auralin 列包含 Auralin 患者的起始剂量和结束剂量
the novodra column contains the start
Novodra 列包含接受 Novodra 治疗的患者
and end dose for patients that were treated with novodra.
的起始剂量和结束剂量
If these two columns both contain two variables,
如果这两列都包含两个变量
start and end dose each,
即起始剂量和结束剂量
where is that missing third variable?
缺少的第三个变量在哪儿呢？
We said there were three variables here, right?
我们说过这里有三个变量 对吧？
Well, the third variable,
第三个变量
treatment, is hidden in the column headers here.
即 治疗 隐藏在这里的列标题中
This is actually one of the most common tidiness issues as per Hadley Wickham.
按照 Hadley Wickham 的观点 这实际上是最常见的一个整洁度问题
Column headers are values not variable names.
列标题是值 不是变量名称
So auralin and novodra are our values for the treatment variable.
Auralin 和 Novodra 是我们对治疗变量给定的值
Whoever structured the data set like this didn't plan very
这个数据集的排列未做好规划
well and wasn't aware of the advantages of tidy data.
也未意识到数据整洁的好处
The final product should look like this.
最终结果应该是这样
Let's zoom in here a bit.
我们在这里将它放大点儿吧
So, for the first patient, Veronika Jindrova, she was treated with auralin,
第一位患者 Veronika Jindrova 接受了 Auralin 胰岛素治疗
the auralin insulin, with the starting dose of 41 units and an ending dose of 48 units.
起始剂量为 41 个单位 结束剂量为 48 个单位
Auralin, 41, 48.
Auralin 41 48
Then for Elliot Richardson he was treated with novodra.
Elliot Richardson 接受了 Novodra 治疗
Starting dose of 40 units,
起始剂量为 40 个单位
ending dose of 45 units and novodra, 40, 45.
结束剂量为 45 个单位 Novodra 40 45
Three separate variables in three separate columns.
三个单独的变量分别在三个单独的列中
Treatment, start dose, end dose.
治疗、起始剂量、结束剂量
You'll learn how to convert the two columns on
在 Pandas 的下一课中 你将学习
the left to the three columns on the right,
如何使用 Melt 函数和 Split 方法编程
programmatically using the melt function and split method in Pandas next lesson.
将左侧两列转换成右侧三列
The melt function specifically is really
特别是 Melt 函数 真的很方便
handy but it can be confusing especially if you never seen it before.
但如果你以前从未见过该函数 则可能会觉得困惑
Next lesson you'll conquer that.
下一课将为你解惑
So let's document this second tidiness issue.
我们来记录第二个整洁问题
And there we go. Here's our observation.
好了 这就是我们的观察情况